# Vincent Walker

London SW19 | 07796 604 660 | vincethewalker@gmail.com | LinkedIn Profile | Website | GitHub

### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE =

Perceptive, proactive, self-taught Ruby on Rails web developer with a commitment to creation of clean, efficient, and accessible code in a functional framework throughout the development lifecycle. A reliable individual with genuine integrity and a strong background in client and stakeholder management, sales, marketing, budget and performance management, providing invaluable all round business expertise.

### **CORE COMPETENCIES** =

- ❖ Web Development
   ❖ Quality Assurance & Control
   ❖ Relationship Management
- ❖ Team Leadership & Development
  ❖ Stakeholder Communication
  ❖ Budget Management

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- ❖ Java Script ❖ Ruby on Rails ❖ HTML ❖ CSS ❖ Bootstrap ❖ Action Cable
- ❖ PostgreSQL ❖ GitHub ❖ Heroku ❖ Testing ❖ SEO (Google) ❖ Tailwind CCS

#### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- From learning to code in 2017, rapidly progressed to creating several original Web Applications
  - Business Den: A SaaS application providing an interface between investors and start-up entrepreneurs
  - 'Let's Chat' a messenger app using Rails Action Cable
  - My Wines an Online shop using the Braintree API
- Wrote functional, unit and integration tests using Minitest, GitHub as Repository and Heroku for production
- Built a bespoke SaaS application (Business Den) using Devise as a User authentication solution, Sendgrid for email integration functionality and STRIPE API for payment authentication using a Credit Card (Business Den), AWS S3 for Image storage.

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

# RUBY ON RAILS WEB DEVELOPER - KING AND MCGAW (6 MONTH FIXED TERM CONTRACT) February 2021 -

- Various projects to improve SEO using Google Tag Manager.
- Developing, improving and maintaining the main retail site working with Rails(6.1) as well as Vue.js and Tailwind CSS on the front end
  - added an enlarge icon on the product page so viewers can enlarge the image as well as see the different frame types.
- Created an 'Make Enquiry' button in the product page when value of Painting (Print) is above £1000
  - Combination of Using Rails Vue and AJAX, I created a function that any print above £1000 a 'Make Enquiry' button will appear on the Product options bar and opening an AJAX form for a customer to contact the customer services directly.
- Worked on a project to migrate away from Mailchimp to a new marketing platform Klaviyo,
  - adding Klaviyo tracker objects inside the various pages Show, Cart, Gallery, using Java Script as well as Ruby

## RUBY ON RAILS WEB DEVELOPER - HOSTELLING INTERNATIONAL June 2019 - November 2020

- Worked on project to migrate the current platform over to a Rails (5.2) starting with the existing testing frame work (Minitest) to make the tests pass.
- Updated the Front end views, on the current platform leading to an overall improved user experience (www.hihostels.com)
  - Using Ruby, HTML, CSS (Bootstrap) and JavaScript, edited and amended the site to match organisations Brand Guidelines
- Developed a 'Recently Viewed' function on the sites main page to enable to a user to book or complete their booking if previously browsed to one of the Hostels
  - Using a session cookie, created a 'pop up' window using Ruby, HTML, JavaScript to complete their booking
  - Developed this to be mobile friendly
  - This created extra revenue for the organisation (using Google analytics)
- Cucumber testing gaining valuable skills and experience in BDD development.

## WEB DEVELOPER / RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - CDC GLOBAL

November 2018 - May 2019

- Working Freelance with CDC Global to create and develop the company Web Site.
  - Initially developed a Static HTML site for the company
  - Redeveloped this into a rails site which enables the user to add their own updates.

### STUDY TO BE A WEB DEVELOPER IN RUBY ON RAILS March 2017 – October 2018

- Career Change towards Web Development. (Self Taught) using several online courses.
- Developed my skills HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Git Hub and Heroku
- Created 3 API's, 'Business Den', 'MyRecipe', 'The Blogger' (https://vincethewalker.herokuapp.com)

# **AYMES INERNATIONAL:** NHS Partnership Manager

Sep 2016 - Feb 2017

Worked to gain market access for a range of Oral Nutritional Supplements with NHS Medicines Management, Community Dietitians and Hospital Dietitians across 30 CCG's in London and Berkshire

### **GLAXOSMITHKLINE:** Vaccines Key Account Manager

2004 - 2016

- In line with GSK's new Digital Strategy, took on Digital Team Lead role, collaborating with Marketing to develop new team website to drive 2 way communication and share information between sales and brand teams
- Collaborated in developing GSK vaccines on-line ordering Platform which enabled healthcare professionals to place their orders on-line in addition to using traditional channels.
- · Acting Regional Business Manager In 2010, to cover sickness, supported the team in implementing strategy, regularly liaising between management and brand teams

**EARLIER CAREER** 

JANSSEN CILAG (SOUTH AFRICA): Specialist Medical Representative HART LTD (SOUTH AFRICA): Sales Representative **SOUTH AFRICAN ARMY MEDICAL SERVICES:** Operational Medic

**EDUCATION** =

Diploma in Sales Management - Damelin College, South Africa Secondary School - Damelin College, South Africa